<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Current Status Of Browser Tracking Prevention | cookiestatus.com</title>
    <link>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Current Status Of Browser Tracking Prevention | cookiestatus.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 13:57:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking protection</title>
      <link>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/tracking-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 15:28:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/tracking-protection/</guid>
      <description>Tracking protection, and similar measures, seek to protect the user against harmful data collection and exploitation by third-party platforms, scripts, and applications.
In short, tracking protection, tracking prevention, anti-tracking, cookie blocking, content blocking, etc. are designed to:
 Identify and classify domains that have been recognized as employing tracking mechanisms harmful to (browsers&amp;rsquo; interpretation of) user privacy. If a script or resource is loaded in a third-party context from such a domain, restrict access to browser storage so that the trackers can not exploit data stored within.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of exploits</title>
      <link>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/summary-of-exploits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 13:12:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/summary-of-exploits/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of ways in which data exploitation is attempted by malicious trackers. On this page, these will be listed superficially.
The problem is that all these methods also serve valid and benign use cases, which means that when browsers seek to prevent these, they also end up preventing non-malicious and non-exploitative use of browser storage.
And this is the nature of the beast. The very same APIs and methodologies that are used, for example, to improve the user experience of the site are simultaneously being repurposed by third parties for data collection and manipulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact</title>
      <link>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 15:29:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/impact/</guid>
      <description>The tracking protection measures taken by browsers have a widespread impact on a variety of things, including web development, advertising and marketing technologies, digital analytics, and user experience optimization.
Websites use cookies and other browser storage for a plethora of things, such as persisting login state, preserving items in a shopping cart, and for presenting tailored experiences in a first-party context, based on what the user has done while visiting the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare</title>
      <link>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/how-to-prepare/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 15:29:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cookiestatus.com/introduction/how-to-prepare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>